Future Plans Survey
Which course are you guys going for?
≪(戸部)みんなはどっち系よ
(結衣)私と姫菜は多分文系
Hina and I are probably going into liberal arts.
Yumiko's still thinking about it.
で 優美子は考え中
(戸部)マジか 俺も文系にすっかな
Really? Maybe I'll go with liberal arts, too...
(優美子)隼人は？
(葉山)一応決めてるけど
What about you, Hayato?
I've kinda decided,
but I'll give it some more thought.
もう少し考えるよ
ふ～ん
Which do you think I should do, Hayato-kun?
隼人君さ どっちがいいと思う？
It's your own life.
≪(葉山)自分のことなんだから
真剣に考えないと後悔するぞ
You need to give it some serious thought, or you'll regret it.
Aww...
≪(戸部)ベ～
≪(大岡)つーか隼人君➡
By the way, Hayato-kun,
雪ノ下さんとつきあってるって
それマジ？
is it true you're going out with Yukinoshita-san?
えッ!?
はあ～？
What?!
≪(葉山)誰が そんな無責任なこと
言ったんだ？
Who said something irresponsible like that?
(大岡)えッ いや… 噂で
Uh...
It's just a rumor...
Did you hear about Hayama-kun?
♬～
聞いた？ 葉山君の話 冬休みに
二人でいるの見た人がいるって
Someone saw them together over winter break!
Yeah, it seems like the real deal, doesn't it?
ああ 何かマジっぽいんでしょ
ゆきのん こっちこっち
Yukinon, over here!
(雪乃)別にこのままでも…
What's wrong with where I am?
(比企谷･結衣･いろは)
誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
Congratulations!
Congrats.
あッ ありがとう…
Th-Thanks.
(いろは)雪ノ下先輩 １月３日が
お誕生日だったんですね
So your birthday is January 3rd, Yukinoshita-senpai?
ちなみに私は４月16日ですよ 先輩
By the way, mine is April 16th, Senpai.
(比企谷)聞いてねえよ ていうか
何でお前までいるわけ？
I didn't ask.
Why are you even here, anyway?
Oh, come on. What's the problem?
まあまあ いいじゃないですか
実はちょっとお願いしたいことが
ありまして
There's actually a little favor I wanted to ask.
あッ そうだ！
雪ノ下先輩って
Oh, right!
Yukinoshita-senpai, are you really going out with Hayama-senpai?
葉山先輩と
つきあってたんですか？
はい？
What?
一色さん
はい…
Isshiki-san.
Y-Yes?
That obviously isn't true.
そんなことあるわけないでしょ
Y-Yeah, you're right!
でッ ですよね
I thought there was no way it could be true!
私も絶対にないって
思ってたんですよ
こないだ出かけたときあるじゃん
Remember when you went out the other day?
それを誰かが見て
誤解してるみたい
Seems like someone saw that and got the wrong idea.
なるほど
げすの勘ぐりというやつね
I see. The petty suspicions of a lowlife.
まあほら
人の噂も四十九日っていうじゃん
Well, you know... They say a rumor only lasts 49 days, right?
七十五日な
≪(いろは)だといいんですけど
That's 75 days.
I hope so...
葉山先輩って 今までこういう
具体的な噂ってなかったんですよ
Hayama-senpai's never had
any rumors specifically about him before, weirdly enough.
不思議と
みんなの葉山隼人って感じで
He's, like, everybody's Hayama Hayato.
So since this rumor came up,
それがですね
噂が出てから 葉山先輩に
there are more people trying to mess with him.
ちょっかいかけようとするのが
増えてるみたいなんですよ
How so?
ちょっかいって？
ぶっちゃけコクるとか
Well, like girls confessing to him,
そこまではいけなくても
確認だけしてアピールみたいな
or if they don't go that far, they try to appeal to him by "just checking."
確認てどういうことかしら
それでアピールになるの？
Checking? On what?
And that appeals to him?
先輩
うん？
Senpai?
今 つきあってる人って
Are you going out with anyone
いますか？
right now?
いない… けど
No... I'm not...
ほら こんな感じですよ
こんな感じ
See? That's what I'm talking about.
言い方の問題じゃん
ねえ ヒッキー
Th-That's just an issue of how you say it!
Right, Hikki?
<いや そのアピール
ぐっとこないことはないですね>
Well, I can't say that wouldn't appeal to me, yes.
<ていうか ぐっときました>
In fact, it sure as hell did.
ヒッキー？
なぜ黙っているのかしら
Hikki?
Why aren't you saying anything?
まッ まあ なに あれだ…
W-Well, anyway, you know...
葉山の状況は分かった
うん よく分かった
I understand what's going on with Hayama.
Yep. I understand very well.
あッ やっぱゆきのん それ似合う
Those really do look great on you!
そッ そうかしら…
D-Do they?
Well...
まあ… そうだな
Yeah.
ありがとう…
Thanks.
Did you always wear glasses, Senpai?
≪(いろは)
先輩って眼鏡してましたっけ？
These reduce blue light.
ブルーライトカットよ
≪(いろは)へ～
Oh...
私もそういう眼鏡
かけてみようかな
Maybe I should try a pair of those, too.
お前 別にパソコン見ねえだろ
見るし パソコン超見るし！
You don't look at the computer that much.
I do! I look at it all the time!
ゆきのん 私にも見せて
Yukinon, let me see it, too!
(メール受信)
Oh, there's an email.
あッ メール来てるね
No Subject
How are you guys decidin' between liberal arts and sciences?
(ドアが開く)
今いい？
Got a minute?
ちょっと話あんだけど
I want to talk to you.
じゃあ 進路相談会の件
よろしくお願いしますね
Well, I appreciate your help with the future plans counseling sessions.
はッ？ 聞いてねえよ
ではでは～
Huh? No one told us about that...
Bye!
で 話って？
So, what'd you want to talk about?
あんた 隼人と何かあんの？
Is something going on with you and Hayato?
別に何もないけれど
昔からの知り合いというだけよ
Nothing of significance.
We've known each other since we were young. That's all.
ﾎﾝﾄに？
私が嘘つくﾒﾘｯﾄが１つでもある？
Is that true?
Would lying benefit me in any way?
そういうの 昔から迷惑だったわ
That sort of thing has always annoyed me.
はッ 何その言い方
マジムカツクんだけど
What? Why do you have to talk like that?
It really pisses me off!
あーし あんたのそういうとこ
ホント嫌い…
I really hate that about y—
Yumiko!
優美子！
その話なら もう説明したじゃん
I already explained that to you before.
ホント偶然会って それだけだって
They just bumped into each other...
That's all it was!
If that's all it was, Hayato wouldn't be so bothered by it.
それだけだったら
隼人 あんなに気にしない
何かあんじゃないの？
別に今のことじゃなくて
Something happened, didn't it?
Even if it's not now,
昔にとか…
something a long time ago...
何かがあったとして
Even if something did happen, and I told you all about it,
それをすべて語って
それで何か変わる？
would it change anything?
あなたは 周りは それを信じる？
Would you, and everyone else, believe it?
結局 意味がないことなのよ
Ultimately, it's meaningless.
あんたのそういうとこ ホント！
That part of you seriously...
まだ何か言いたいことはある？
Is there something else you'd like to say?
ちょっと落ち着いてって ねッ
Come on, calm down. Okay?
You, too. Calm down.
お前も落ち着けって
落ち着いているわ
I am calm.
こういうの 慣れているのよ
I'm used to this sort of thing.
私は近しい人が理解しているなら
それだけで構わないから
As long as the people closest to me understand, that's enough.
Obviously. That's exactly why.
≪(優美子)そんなの当たり前だし
だからなんじゃん
えッ？
Huh?
The thing about the people closest to you.
近しい人ってやつ
それになりたいから
知りたいんじゃん
That's what I want to be. That's why I asked.
No Subject
How are you guys decidin' between liberal arts and sciences?
お前が知りたいのは
昔何があったかじゃないんだな
What you want to know isn't what happened a long time ago, is it?
I... just... I mean...
あーしは ただ 何…？
何か もうちょっと一緒だったら
いいかなって思っただけで…➡
I just...
thought it'd be nice if we could be together a little longer...
その… このままみんな
All of us, I mean.
隼人 最近距離あるし
Hayato's been distant lately.
Even I realize this is weird, but...
こんなの変て 自分でも…
だけど ほか よく分かんないし
I don't know anything else...
It's not weird.
変じゃない 全然変じゃないよ
It's not weird at all.
It's only natural to want to stay together.
一緒にいたいって思うの それって
すごく当たり前のことだもん
Miura probably wants to know
<三浦は 葉山の進路が>
what future course Hayama will take, and what he'll do beyond that.
<その先に続く あの男のあり方が
知りたいんだろう>
And she knows things can't stay the way they are now...
<きっと 今のままでは
いられないことを分かっていて>
<それでもなお
隣にい続けることを望んで>
But that just makes her want to stay close to him all the more.
でもな 三浦
But you know, Miura...
葉山が教えないってことは
Doesn't the fact that he won't tell anyone
知られたくない
ことなんじゃねえのか
mean that he doesn't want anyone to know?
He might not like being asked.
嫌がられるかもしれないぞ
Hey, Hikki!
ちょ… ヒッキー！
比企谷君
Hikigaya-kun...
Do you still want to know?
それでも 知りたいか？
知りたい
I do.
それでも知りたい
I still want to know.
それしかないから
It's the only choice I have.
分かった 何とかする
All right. I'll do something about it.
Here. Take this.
はい これ
おお サンキュー
Oh, thanks.
<早速使ってるんですね>
Already using them, I see...
お前ら もう帰っていいぞ
You guys can go on home.
But it doesn't feel right leaving it all to you.
でも 任せきりっていうのも何か…
Nah, it'll be easier to ask him alone. I think.
いや 一人のほうが聞きやすい
多分
では 任せてしまって悪いけれど
Well, then... Sorry to leave it all to you.
別に 仕事ならしょうがねえよ
No big deal. Work is work, can't help that.
似合わないセリフね
I never expected to hear that from you.
俺の進路？ 誰かに頼まれたのか？
My future plans?
Did someone ask you to ask me?
No, just... for reference.
いや まあ… 参考に
Then can I ask you a favor, too?
じゃあ 俺からも頼んでいいか？
うん？
そういう煩わしいの
やめてくれないか
Could you stop being so intrusive?
なんて 相反すること言われたら
今度はどうするんだ？
If I said something contrary like that, what would you do?
I'd cross that bridge when the time came.
そりゃ そんとき考える
I see.
そうか
さっきの質問
答えは想像に任せるよ
As for your question,
I'll leave the answer to your imagination.
≪(戸塚)進路か➡
Future plans, huh?
せっかく長くテニスやってるから
関係することがいいかな
Since I've been playing tennis for so long,
I guess I'd like something related to that.
だったら推薦とかないのか？
Can't you get a recommendation or something, then?
そんなのごく一部だよ
Only a precious few get those.
うちの学校だと
葉山君くらいじゃないかな
At our school, only someone like Hayama-kun would have a chance.
みんな 解散 また放課後ね
Guys! Dismissed!
See you after school!
≪(部員達)はい
Sure!
This doesn't suit me?
似合わない？
あッ いや…
No... I just didn't know you did captain-ish stuff like that.
そういう部長っぽいの
知らなかったからな
ちょっと驚いた
結構ちゃんとやってるでしょ
It surprised me a little.
I'm doing a pretty solid job, right?
ちょっと頼りないかもだけど
I might be a little unreliable, though.
いや 頼れるさ
Nah, I could rely on you.
まだ分かんねえけど そのだな…
Not that I'd know yet, of course...
でも 多分頼る
But I'm pretty sure I could.
うん
Yeah.
あッ 遅い 先輩
You're late, Senpai!
と…
お二人もありがとうございます
And... you guys, too! Thanks for coming!
やっはろー いろはちゃん
何をすればいいかしら
Yahello, Iroha-chan.
What do you want us to do?
ちょっと
並べ直さないとなんですよ➡
We have to rearrange all this stuff.
卒業生にも来てもらってますので
Some of the alumni came to help.
Alumni?
卒業生…
Hey, it's Hikigaya-kun!
(陽乃)おッ 比企谷君じゃん
ひゃっはろー
Yahello!
姉さん 聞きたいことがあるの
うん？➡
Nee-san, there's something I want to ask you.
隼人の進路？ 何だ そんなこと
何か知っているの？
Hayato's future plans? Is that all?
Do you know anything?
一人で
やるようになったと思ったら
And I thought you could handle things on your own now.
ま～た昔みたいに人に頼る
Here you are relying on others again.
ちっちゃいころは
それもかわいかったんだけどね
That was cute when you were little, but now...
自分でよく考えなさい
Think about it on your own.
ゆきのん…
Yukinon...
駅まで送ってよ
Walk me to the station.
はッ？
Huh?
It's not often you get a chance to walk home with a gorgeous older girl like this.
こんな美人のお姉さんと
一緒に帰れるなんて
なかなかないんだぞ～
じゃ 行こっか
Well, ready to go?
へ～い…
Sure.
雪乃ちゃんは何学部志望とかって
聞いてる？
Have you heard which curriculum Yukino-chan wants to go into?
No, I haven't.
いや 聞いてないです
Well, I guess she wouldn't volunteer the information.
あの子は自分からは言わないか
比企谷君 ちゃんと聞いといてよね
今度答え合わせね
Make sure you ask her, okay, Hikigaya-kun?
We'll check each other's answers.
それは答え合わせとは
言わないんじゃないですかね
I don't think you'd call that "checking each other's answers."
細かいこと気にしない➡
Don't sweat the little details!
そういえば
隼人には直接聞いたの？
By the way, did you try asking Hayato directly?
ああ 何か色々言って
教えてくれなかったんで
Yeah. He said some stuff, but wouldn't tell me.
ふ～ん そっか
隼人も期待してたんだね
Huh... I see.
Hayato was hoping for it, too...
何を？
For what?
見つけてくれることを かな
For someone to find him... maybe?
みんなの葉山隼人か
Everyone's Hayama Hayato, huh?
《俺は君が思っているほど
いいやつじゃない》
I'm not the good guy you think I am.
☎(戸塚)もしもし
ああ 俺だ 悪いな こんな時間に
Hello?
Hey, it's me.
Sorry to call this late.
☎ううん どうしたの？
It's okay. What's up?
頼みがある
I need a favor.
Hayama-senpai! Good luck going for your second consecutive win!
葉山先輩 ２連覇目指して
頑張ってくださ～い
H-Hayato... g-good luck!
はッ 隼人 頑張ってね
うん
ついでに
先輩も頑張ってくださいね
And good luck to you, too, Senpai!
おう！
Thanks!
No, not you, Tobe-senpai.
≪(いろは)
戸部先輩のことじゃないです
G-Good luck!
がッ 頑張れ～
頑張って
Good luck.
Well, let's do this.
<じゃ やりますかね>
On your marks!
(平塚)位置について 用意
Set!
(スタートの合図)
<自転車通学でよかった>
Damn, I'm glad I ride a bike to school!
Otherwise, there's no way I could run this long!
<そうでもないと
ろくすっぽ走れねえよ これ>
I'm impressed you're keeping up.
よくついてくるな
Yeah, well...
まあな ペース配分考えなきゃ
できなくはねえよ
As long as I don't think about pacing myself, it's not impossible.
I wonder how people feel as they approach a halfway point in a trial.
<苦行の折り返し地点に
近づいたとき>
Do they despair at the knowledge that half the trial still remains?
<人はどう思うだろうか>
<まだ半分もあると絶望するか>
Or do they feel relieved to have made it halfway through?
<あるいは もう半分まできたと
安堵するか>
Most would probably feel one of the two.
<多くの場合 そのどちらかだろう>
<そして そのどちらの感情も
人の心に隙をつくる>
And both of those emotions create openings in people's hearts.
That's why I've pushed myself this far.
<だから ここまでムチャをした>
三浦は
女よけには都合がよかったか？
Was Miura handy for keeping girls away?
どうなんだよ 役に立ったのか？
Well? Was she useful?
Be quiet for a minute.
少し黙れ
あッ…
文理選択 どっち選んだんだ？
教えない
Did you pick liberal arts or sciences?
I'm not telling you.
Then let me put it another way.
じゃあ言い方を変える
理系にしろ お前が
どっち選んだかなんて知らん
Pick sciences.
I don't know which one you had chosen,
別に興味もない
and I don't really care.
But it can still be changed, so change it!
でも まだ変更できるから変えとけ
それしか
お前の望む条件を満たせない
That's the only way to meet your condition!
Condition?
条件？
You told me to stop being intrusive, right?
煩わしいのを
やめてくれっつったろ
In other words,
つまり お前はみんなの望む
葉山隼人をやめたいんだ
you want to stop being the Hayama Hayato everyone wants!
理系なら そもそも人が少ないし
女子も少ない
If you go with sciences, there won't be as many people,
and there aren't many girls.
You can put distance between you and the problems intruding in your life.
お前が煩わされてる問題からは
とりあえず距離を置ける
Plus, if your choice doesn't match theirs,
それに 進路が違うなら
みんな納得して離れられるわな
they'll all accept it and drift away from you.
自然消滅なら 誰も傷つかないし
If it ends naturally, nobody gets hurt,
誰の期待も裏切らずにすむ
and you won't have to betray anyone's expectations.
やっぱり
仲良くできなかっただろうな
I was right. We never could've been friends.
Huh?
はッ？
俺は君が嫌いだ
I don't like you.
O-Oh...
君に劣っていると感じる
そのことがたまらなく嫌だ
I feel inferior to you,
and I can't stand that.
同格であってほしいんだよ
I wanted us to be equals,
君に負けることを肯定するために
so I could accept losing to you.
だから 君の言うとおりにはしない
So I won't do as you say.
悪いな 連覇阻止しちゃって
Sorry for blocking your second consecutive win.
No, I'll win. That's what I do.
いや 勝つさ それが俺だ
それに 君に負けたくないんだよ
Besides...
I don't want to lose to you.
うわッ！
<クソッ かっこいいじゃねえか>
Damn it...
Why is he so cool?!
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ](いろは)葉山先輩
おめでとうございます
Congratulations, Hayama-senpai!
私 絶対勝つと思ってましたよ
I knew for sure you'd win!
皆さんの応援のおかげで
最後まで駆け抜けられました
I was able to finish the race thanks to all of your support.
ありがとうございます
Thank you.
Yumiko.
優美子
えッ？
いろは
Iroha.
ありがとう
Thanks.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ](いろは)は～い
葉山先輩に拍手
Okay! A round of applause for Hayama-senpai!
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]２位以下は
別にいらないですよね
I don't need to announce who placed after him, right?
雪ノ下さんとつきあってた
わけじゃなかったんだ
So he wasn't really going out with Yukinoshita-san?
≪(女子生徒)
やっぱり噂は噂でしかないね
I guess rumors are just rumors.
Infirmary
比企谷君
どうしたんだ お前
Hikigaya-kun...
What are you doing here?
少し休んでいたら
棄権させられたのよ
I stopped to rest for a bit, and they made me forfeit.
比企谷君は ケガ？
ああ ちょっとな
Did you hurt yourself?
Yeah, a little.
向こうで手当てを
受けてきたらよかったのに
You could've had them treat it out there.
ゴールしたときには
いなかったんだよ
No one was there by the time I crossed the finish line.
そう 間が悪いわね
Oh. I guess it was bad timing.
それとも 運が悪いのかしら
あるいは目 もしくは…
Or maybe it's your luck that was bad.
Or maybe your eyes, or...
性格とか意地とか色々悪いよ
My personality, my pride... A lot of me is bad.
ついでに手癖も悪いみたいね
Looks like your hands don't work so well, either.
Sit over there.
そこに座りなさい
いや これくらいは自分でできる
Uh, I can do this much by myself.
いいから
Just sit.
あの… しみるんですけど
H-Hey... That stings.
仕方ないでしょ
殺菌してるんだから
I can't help that. It's to kill the germs.
比企谷君に効果があるのは当然よ
It only makes sense that it would be effective on you.
人をバイキン扱いするの やめてね
Would you stop treating me like a germ?
葉山君と走っていたようだけれど
何か聞けたの？
It looked like you were running with Hayama-kun.
Did you get any answers?
ああ 少なくとも理系じゃないな
Well...
If nothing else, he's not going into sciences.
変な言い方ね
That's a funny way to put it.
できた
All done.
あッ これありがとな
Uh... Thanks for this.
いえ 大したことでもないから
It's fine. It's not a big deal.
なあ 進路どっちに進むか
聞いてもいいか？
Hey...
Can I ask which course you're going into?
あなたがそういうことを
聞くのって初めてね
That's the first time you've asked me a question like that.
Is it?
そうか？
一応 文系ということには
なっているわ
For what it's worth, I'll be going into liberal arts.
だから とりあえず
So...
For the time being, we'll all stay together.
みんな一緒ね
まッ カテゴリーの上ではな
Well, in terms of categories, I guess.
じゃ そろそろ教室戻るわ
ええ
Okay, I'm gonna head back to the classroom.
All right.
じゃあ また
See you later.
ビックリした
ああ ヒッキー
Whoa, you scared me!
Oh, Hikki...
何だ 由比ヶ浜か
ああ… うん
Oh, it's you, Yuigahama.
Ah, yeah... I just got here...
ちょうど今来たとこなんだけど
ゆきのん 遅くなってごめんね
Yukinon, sorry I took so long.
優美子達 打ち上げに
行くらしいけど どうしよっか
Yumiko and the gang are going to the after-party.
Want to go?
Sorry for the trouble that crazy rumor caused you.
(葉山)すまない
変な噂とか迷惑をかけた
迷惑というほどでもないわ
It didn't particularly trouble me.
それに 気遣ってくれたことには
感謝しているの
And...
I'm grateful that you were concerned for me.
君は 少し変わったな
You've changed a bit.
I don't know about that.
どうかしら
ただ 昔とは色んなことが違うから
It's just that so many things are different from back then.
ゆきのん 料理来たよ
Yukinon! The food's here!
何かすっごい鳥 超丸焼いてるの
It's all these chickens!
And they're totally cooked whole!
やっぱり彼女は少し変わったな
She really has changed a bit.
もう陽乃さんの影は
追ってないように見える
It looks like she's not chasing Haruno-san's shadow anymore.
けど それだけのことでしかない
いいんじゃねえの それで
But it's no more than that.
Isn't that good enough?
気付いてないのか？
何が？
You haven't noticed?
Noticed what?
まあ 分かってないなら
それでもいいか
Well, if you don't know, I guess that's fine.
そうだ
１つ言い忘れてたことがあった
Oh, right. There's something I forgot to tell you.
うん？
進級や進学程度で
Things like moving up to the next grade
人間関係はリセットされないよ
いや 全然リセットされるぞ
or to college don't reset relationships.
Yes, that totally does reset them.
それは比企谷だけだろ
俺と君は違う
That's only for you.
You and I aren't the same.
じゃあ何で誰にも
進路を言わなかったんだよ
Then why wouldn't you tell anyone which course you're going into?
それしか選びようが
なかったものを選んでも
If I chose something because I had no other choice,
それを自分の選択とは
いわないだろ
I couldn't call it my own decision.
１つ言い忘れてた
There's something I forgot to tell you.
俺も お前が嫌いだよ
I don't like you, either.
そうか
I see.
そうやって面と向かって
言われたのは 初めてかもしれない
You might be the first person who ever said that to my face.
それでも 俺は選ばない 何も
Still...
I won't choose.
Anything.
それが一番いい方法だと信じてる
I believe that's the best way to go.
Each and Every Time,
Hayama Hayato Lives Up to Expectations.
≪(葉山)自己満足だよ
It's my self-satisfaction.
With the Answer He Seeks Still Out of Reach,
the Real Thing He Craves Keeps Going Wrong.
♬～
Oh... Hayato's going into liberal arts?
Then maybe I'll do that, too.
Are you sure you should make that decision so easily?
There's nothing I particularly want to do.
I can put off starting college, but this doesn't work that way.
It's gonna be tough to put up with him.
What? I don't need to hear that from you, Hikio.
And, you know...
I think all of him is cool, including his troublesome side.
I see...
It could've been that much simpler...
(優美子)隼人 文系いくんだ
あーしもそれでいいかな
そんな簡単に決めてしまって
いいの？
(優美子)やりたいこととか
別にないし➡
受験は浪人できるけど
これってそうはいかないし
大変だぞ あれの相手は
(優美子)ヒキオに言われるまでも
ないんですけど➡
そういう 何…
めんどいのも含めてさ➡
やっぱいいって思うんじゃん
そっか もっと簡単でよかったんだ